Guide to the Yale Literary Magazine Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Yale Literary Magazine records
1847-1959
RU 516
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
2
(6 boxes)
The records consist of manuscripts submitted to the Yale Literary Magazine. An index (circa 1847) and materials relating to a 1950 library exhibit and a symposium on Josef Albers are also included.
Yale Literary Magazine
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 40 (YRG 40), Records of Yale clubs, societies, and organizations.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
The Yale Literary Magazine was established in 1836.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of manuscripts submitted to the Yale Literary Magazine. An index (circa 1847) and materials relating to a 1950 library exhibit and a symposium on Josef Albers are also included.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Yale Literary Magazine; College student newspapers and periodicals; Albers, Josef, 1888-1976; Yale University -- Students
- Publications Yale Literary Magazine, 1847, 1935-1959; Accession 19ND-A-405
  - Angell, President James R.; Anonymous; Arbila, Robert Jr.; Auchincloss, John W.,I.; Auchincloss, Louis S., 1934-1939 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bacon, Leonard; Baker, Edward Joseph; Barry, Phillip; Beebe, Lucius, 1909, 1918, 1926, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Beer, Thomas; Benét, Stephen Vincent; Bordon, Arthur Murray; Borst, William Alvord, 1911, 1919, 1937, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Brombon, Edmund; Bunker, Charles C.; Burrows, Edwin Gladding; Canby, Henry Seidel, 1899, 1936, 1936, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Carpenter, Gardner C.; Carver, Charles; Catherwood, Hugh; Chapell, George Shepard; Chubb, Thomas Caldecut; Cole, William K., 1899, 1922, 1935, 1936, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Cunningham, Hugh T.; Davis, Luther Berryhill; Davis, William Curtis Carroll; de Mare, George, 1934-1938 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Editor's Miscellany, Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Editor's Table, Undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Elder, Robert Duncan; Farrar, John; Ferguson, John H.; Frank, Waldo, 1911, 1936, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Garran, Anthony N.B., 1939 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Gill, Brenden Michael, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Gordon, G. Arthur, Jr., 1934 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Hammond, J. Ogden, Jr., 1934 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Hayward, Fred Harry, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Heinl, Robert Debs, Jr., 1937 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Howe, Peter, Undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Hume, Cyril, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Jenkins, Brooke Allen, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Keeler, Stephen Edwards, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - King, Rufus Frederick, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Kipling, Rudyard; Krug, Thomas K., 1935 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Leader; Lewis, Sinclair, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Makepeace, LeRoy McKim; MacKish, Archibald; Miller, Townsend; Millis, Walter, 1915, 1920, 1933, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Nelson, Harry William; Nettleton, George Henry; Nichols, James Hastings, 1896, 1933, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Olmsted, Ashley Williams; Phelps, William Lyon; Pinchot, Gifford, 1887, 1889, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Raymond, Edward A.; Robinson, Dwight E., Jr.; Rodgers, Curtis C.; Russell, Thomas Wright, Jr., 1936-1939 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Seymour, Charles; Soule, George H.; Starr, Roger; Stinson, Henry L.; Towle, Hannibal S., 1908, 1933, 1935, 1930, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Wanning, Andrews; Waring, Antonio Johnston; "What Yale is Reading;" Wiilder, Thornton; Yost, James Mitchell, 1920, 1934, 1937, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Manuscripts A, 1936-1940 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Manuscripts B, 1936-1940 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Manuscripts C, 1936-1940 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Manuscripts D, 1936-1940 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Manuscripts E, 1936-1940 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Manuscripts F, 1936-1940 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Manuscripts G, 1936-1940 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Manuscripts H, 1936-1940 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Manuscripts J, 1936-1940 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Manuscripts K, 1936-1940 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Manuscripts M, 1936-1940 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Manuscripts M, 1936-1940 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Manuscripts N, 1936-1940 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Manuscripts P, 1936-1940 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Manuscripts R, 1936-1940 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Manuscripts S, 1936-1940 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Manuscripts T, 1936-1940 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Manuscripts V, 1936-1940 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Manuscripts W, 1936-1940 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Manuscripts Y, 1936-1940 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Manuscripts A, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Manuscripts B, Undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Manuscripts C, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Manuscripts D, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Manuscripts E, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Manuscripts F, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Manuscripts G, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Manuscripts H, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Manuscripts J, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Manuscripts K, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Manuscripts L, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Manuscripts M-N, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Manuscripts O-R, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Manuscripts S-T, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Manuscripts unidentified, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Manuscripts unidentified, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Manuscripts W, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Index, circa 1847 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Library exhibit, "Dylan Thomas" edition, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Library exhibit, "International" edition, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Library exhibit, manuscripts/notes from April, 1858 issue, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Poundiana, Undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Poundiana, Undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Press clippings, 1957-1959 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Library exhibit scrapbook, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Symposiums, Undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Pictures from a symposium, Undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Re: Prizes, Undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous, Undated (Box 6, Folder 4)